

# Europass Curriculum Vitae

My LinkedIN profile





#### Personal information

Surname / First name

Address

C33

Telephone

Personal Email

0.00..a. =...a.

Nationality

Date of birth

Gender

Bio

#### **Buracchi Marco**

95, Via Pier Capponi, 50132, Firenze (FI), Italy

+39 3498362954

Personal: ma.buracchi@gmail.com PEC: marco.buracchi@postecert.it

19/12/1985

Male

Italian

I'm an ICS CyberSecurity Specialist at H-ON Consulting in Prato and I attend the Short Specialisation Programme (Master I livello) in Cybersecurity at the Pisa University. I graduated in October 2018 with 110/110 cum laude at the master's degree in computer science, "resilient and secure cyber physical systems" curricula. My master thesis was on "Side-Channel Attacks and speculative execution". Before, I obtained the bachelor degree in computer science in 2015 with 110/110 cum laude.

## Desired employment/ Occupational field

# IT/OT/IoT security, Software Development & Research

## **Education and training**

Dates

02/2019 - 03/2020 (expected)

Title of qualification awarded

Principal subjects

Short Specialisation Programme - Master I livello in cybersecurity
Applied Cryptography and Access Control, Network Security & Ethical hacking, Op-

erating Systems Security, Digital Forensics, Cyber Intelligence, Mobile and cloud security, Legal aspects of cybersecurity, Secure system configuration, device hardening and firewall management, Risk monitoring for networks and applications, Secure application development (network, mobile, cloud)

Occupational skills covered Expert in security analysis

7

Expert in security analysis of applications and IT systems, expert in cyber attacks analysis

Organization University of Pisa, Department of Information Engineering

CNR (Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche) - Institute of Informatics and Telematics

ISCED/EQF level

Dates

01/10/2015 - 12/10/2018

Title of qualification awarded

Master's degree (Laurea Magistrale) in Resilient and Secure Cyber Physical Systems

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered Security engineering, Security and network management, Distributed programming for IoT, Multivariate analysis and statistical learning, Coding theory and computer security, Advanced techniques (and tools) for software development, Advanced topics in programming languages, Computer forensics, Models of sequential and concurrent systems, Quantitative analysis of systems, Real-time and critical systems, Systems modeling for verification, Advanced numerical analysis

Organization Final grade ISCED/EQF level University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude

7

08/08/2017 - 12/08/2017 Dates

Title of qualification awarded Cornell, Maryland, Max Planck pre-doctoral research school

Principal subjects/Occupational Security and privacy, social systems, distributed systems, machine learning, programskills covered ming languages, and verification

> Organization Max Planck institute for software systems, Cornell University, University of Maryland

01/10/2012 - 09/10/2015 Dates

Title of qualification awarded Bachelor's Degree (Laurea Triennale) in Computer Science.

> University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences Organization

110/110 cum laude Final grade

ISCED/EQF level 6

Work experiences

**Dates** 13/02/2020 - now

Occupation or position held ICS CyberSecurity Specialist

Main activities ICS CyberSecurity consulting, R&D

Name and address of employer H-ON consulting, Via Lepanto, 23, 59100 Prato PO

Type of business or sector ICS CyberSecurity

> 01/10/2019 - now Dates

Occupation or position held Junior Security Engineer

> Main activities Vulnerability assessment, penetration testing, research and development.

Name and address of employer Florence Consulting Group, Via Luciano Lama, 23, 50019 Sesto Fiorentino FI

Type of business or sector IT Security

> 28/11/2018 - 31/08/2019 Dates

Occupation or position held Private tutor

> Main activities One-on-one in-house tutoring for middle-school, high-scool and university students.

Name and address of employer Centro didattico Matemagia - Via Baracca 166, Firenze

Type of business or sector Private education

> 01/04/2015 - 01/10/2016 **Dates**

Occupation or position held Research helper

Main activities and I took part in AMADEOS project (Architecture for Multi-criticality Agile Dependable Evolutionary Open System-of-Systems) funded under the European Commission's responsibilities FP7, supporting research in definition, implementation and evaluation of mechanisms and solutions for the resilient management of the time in the smart grid and smart

cities. http://amadeos-project.eu/

Name and address of employer Prof. Andrea Bondavalli, Resilient Computing Lab, Università di Firenze Type of business or sector Research and experimentation of dependable architectures and systems

01/05/2006 - 01/09/2012

Occupation or position held **CNC Machinist and Programmer** 

> AutoCAD drawing, CNC programming and cutting (laser cutting, machining center, Main activities

wire EDM)

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

01/09/2004 - 01/05/2006 Technical employee

Manufacturing industry

Occupation or position held

Main activities and responsibilities

Dates

Direct measurement in field, fixture designer, autoCAD drawing, cutting programs developer

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector Emmedi srl, Arezzo, Italy Manufacturing industry

### Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue Other language(s) Self-assessment European level(\*)

#### **English**

Computer skills and competences

> Artistic skills and competences

Driving licence(s)

# Italian

Understanding			Speaking			,	Writing		
Ĺ	Listening Reading		Reading	Spoken interaction		Spoken production			
C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user

<sup>(\*)</sup> Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

Nuova 230AR, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2006 - 01/05/2008)

Gabry packing, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2008 - 01/09/2012)

Very good computer skills, learned as self-taught and through the University. Good knowledge in the use of Kali Linux OS and various IT security and cyber intelligence tools (among the best known: Metasploit, OpenVAS, Nessus, Legion, Maltego). High expertise with many tools such as Apache NiFi, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Maven, Github, virtualization tools, Docker, test-framework.

I studied piano at conservatoire for 4 years. I can play guitar. I love skiing and I'm a futsal goalkeeper for more than 10 years

Driver's license (Italian Republic, full European validity), category A (motorcycle owner) and B (car owner).

### **Additional informations**

#### References

Prof. Michele Boreale, University of Florence, Italy, michele.boreale(AT)unifi.it; Prof. Rosario Pugliese, University of Florence, Italy, rosario.pugliese(AT)unifi.it;

#### **Personal interests**

IT security, Technology, Mathematics, Physics and Science in general. Books, Music and all kind of sports. Travelling around the world.

> I hereby authorize the processing of the personal data contained in this CV in compliance with the Italian Personal Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 of 30 June 2003 and GDPR 679/16 art.13)